我们每年都有一次许愿的机会
We all get at least one good wish a year
对着蛋糕上的蜡烛
Over the candles on our birthday.
有人不断许愿
Some of us throw in more--
漂亮的睫毛
On eyelashes...
清澈的喷泉
Fountains...
一夜成名
Lucky stars.
时不时的
And every now and then...
某个愿望得以实现
One of those wishes comes true.
我不想去上班了
Oh, I don't want to go to work.
这里多暖和  就像个蚕茧
It's warm in here. it's a cocoon.
不用对着克里斯蒂娜的臭脸
No cristina with the mean face.
不用抢救生命
No lives to save.
来场急速"战斗"吧  能让我舒坦些
A quickie? a quickie will make me feel better.
当然要来一场急速"战斗"
Yeah, we definitely need a quickie.
然后呢
So what then?
心满意足了吗
Is it as good as we hoped?
我们是沉浸在欢乐之中
Do we bask in the warm glow of our happiness?
还是
Or...
陡然发现
Do we just notice
还有一长串愿望
We've got a long list of other wishes
尚未许下
Waiting to be wished?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
什么  谢谢
What? oh. yeah, thank you.
听着  时间紧迫  都听好了
Whew. okay, we gotta move fast, people, so focus.
欧麦利去pit  克莱夫跟着我
Uh, o'malley, the pit. karev, you're with me.
有个手术要做  斯蒂文斯  诊所预算该算好了
We've got a surgery. stevens, the clinic budget is due.
-杨  格蕾  在外伤室等主任  -什么  为什么
- Yang, grey, wait for the chief at the trauma bay. - what? why?
-我们俩  -是的  你们俩  我不知道目的
- Both of us? - yes, both of you. I don't know what.
也不知道原因  你们去就是了
I don't know why. just go.
两人都愤怒于沉默之中
They're all silent rage-y.
-什么情况  -你看
- What do you got? - take a look.
什么情况
So what do we have?
caldwell  监狱里那个
Caldwell-- as in the prison?
没错
Yeah.
这位贵宾的情况研究清楚了
You've read up on our V.I.P.?
是的  多处刺伤  浑身是伤
Yes. multiple stab wounds, badly beaten--
手术将全程有守卫看守
He'll have guards with him at all times.
带着手铐脚镣手术
Cuffs stay on, leg irons stay on.
留心注射器针头等尖锐物
Watch your syringes, sharps and pins.
我可不想出差错
I don't want any accidents.
他到了  你们四人协助我  实习生没份
And he's here. you four are my team. no interns.
此事动静越小越好
I want to keep this as quiet as possible.
让他快进快出
Get him in and out quickly,
-做完手术快速送走  -PDR是什么
- Patch him up and get him on his way. - what's "p.d.r."?
尽快完成手术
Get him out of trauma as fast as you can.
那些守卫很容易引起注意
Those guards are going to attract a lot of attention.
主任  这上面盖有PDR  是什么意思
Uh, sir, it's stamped p.d.r. what is p.d.r.?
囚犯
Prisoner...
死囚
Death row.
各位早上过得如何
How's everybody doing this morning?
实习医生格蕾 第五季 第11集
Greys Anatomy S05E11
登先生  能听见我说话吗
Mr. Dunn, can you hear me?
-你的声音真美  -好了
- You have a lovely voice. - okay...
全套外伤检查
We need a trauma series.
我也不愿打扰  但我
Oh, I hate to be a bother, but my--
我的腿疼得不行
My legs really, really hurt.
我的腿被捅了吗
Was I stabbed in the leg?
我们检查过你的腿  未发现异常
We checked your legs. we didn't find anything.
-还需要胸椎和腰椎拍片  -做CT就行了
- We should add t-spine and l-spine films. - we're gonna get a c.t. anyway.
-多余的拍片是无用功  -多拍几张又何妨
- Extra films are a waste of time. - couple more shots can't hurt.
要是我的腿没被捅  为何我感觉如此
If I wasn't stabbed in the leg, why does it feel like I was?
听着  你说的越少  我们越能专心工作
You know, the less you talk, the more we can work.
德瑞克
Derek.
没关系  增进了解后他就会友善些
That's okay. he'll warm up as we get to know each other.
我不觉得
I don't think so.
走着瞧  你我之间并无天壤之别
You'll see. we're not that different, you and i.
人们见我们时还活着
People are alive when they meet us,
然后峰回路转
And then that all changes somehow.
你好
Hi there.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我向你问好
I'm saying hello.
听着
Listen...
我的挚友向我提出要求
My best friend made one simple request--
让我别碰你  我失信了
That I not get anywhere near you--and I slipped.
那晚很美妙  你也很美妙
It was fantastic. you're fantastic.
但是不会再发生了
But it's not gonna happen again...
永远
Ever.
好吧
Okay.
该死的
Damn it! ow.
看来你髋部摔断了
Yep, I think you broke your hip.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
拜托
Come on.
你跟谁说话呢
Who are you talking to?
上个月我在人行道上摔了一跤
Last month, I tripped on the sidewalk
断了一根肋骨
And I cracked a rib.
四月  我洗澡时摔倒  断了手
In april, I fell in the shower and I broke my arm.
一月  做瑜伽时断了两根手指  瑜伽啊
January? broke two fingers doing yoga. yoga.
这是今年第六次了
This is my sixth break in a year.
所以我盯着苍天
And so I stare at the heavens,
虽然对上天毫无信仰
And without any belief in a higher power
但我必须找人责怪  于是我大喊
But a desperate need to blame someone, I yell
-TMD拜托  -这个怎么样
- "come freakin' on." ow. - okay, tell you what?
去整形外科做一些检查
How about we call ortho, have 'em run a few tests?
总比仰天大叫要有用些
Might be a little more satisfying than shouting to the heavens.
谢谢
thank you.
杰克逊 普雷斯科特
Jackson Prescott!
你又长高了
You shot up again?
-没有  -那怎么看上去这么高
- No, I didn't. - well, then why do you look so big?
-因为你矮  -我一直都矮  你长高了
- 'cause you're short. - I've always been short. you grew.
贝利医生  我要给杰克逊做检查
Dr. Bailey, while I check out jackson,
请你给梅林达解释一下今天的手术
Why don't you take Melinda through today's procedure?
没问题
Yeah, no problem.
来吧
Come on.
看到了没  他的肤色更黄了
Did you see? he looks more yellow.
kenley医生会为他检查肝功能
Okay, Dr. Kenley's gonna check his liver function test.
开始前  我先说明一下
Look, before we start, let me explain something.
杰克逊做过十二次肠切除术
Jackson has had 12 bowel resections.
每次杰克逊来这儿  肯利医生都会叫我
Dr. Kenley calls me anytime Jackson's here.
梅林达是个单身母亲
Now Melinda is a single mom.
她疯狂工作只为确保
She works like a maniac to make sure
-他可爱的儿子能付得起医药费  -玛兰达
- That beautiful boy has health coverage. - Miranda--
让我说  这个家庭十分特殊
Don't even start. this is a special family.
我们要尽可能地帮她
We do whatever we can to help.
没有这个必要  我
It's really not necessary. I--
有必要
It is necessary.
我们会照顾好你儿子
We'll take good care of your kid.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我们谈谈手术
Now let's talk about the surgery.
我这次能吃棒棒糖了吗
Are you gonna let me have a lollipop this time?
-我的胃好多了  -是吗
- My stomach's not so bad right now. - it's not?
那我怎么会要从那里再切除一小块呢
So how come I'm about to cut a piece out of it again?
给我一根棒棒糖  如果我能控制住
Give me one of the lollipops, and if I keep it down,
-就不需要做手术了  -我可不这么
- We don't have to do the operation. - I'm not sure that's gonna...
我可不
I'm not...
-我  -肯利医生
- I'm...  - Dr. Kenley?
杰克逊  按下蓝色按钮
Jackson, hit the blue button.
就在你身后  蓝色按钮
Right behind you-- hit the blue button.
蓝色警报  四楼  蓝色警报  四楼
Code blue, fourth floor. Code blue, fourth floor.
天哪  发生了什么
Oh, my god. what happened?
他昏过去了
He just fell over.
蓝色警报  四楼  蓝色警报  四楼
Code blue, fourth floor. Code blue, fourth floor.
主任  坏消息
Sir, uh... I have some bad news.
约旦 肯利刚才冠心病发
It looks like Jordan Kenley just had a massive coronary.
来不及抢救就已经不行了
He was gone before he hit the deck.
他的妻子正在赶来
Uh, his wife's on the way.
她可能会找你谈谈  他妻子
She'll probably want to speak to you, the wife,
需要听些安慰的话
Hear something reassuring--
受人缅怀和尊敬的同事
He'll be missed, honored colleague,
为医院呕心沥血工作多年
Uh... decades of service.
主任  你没事吧
Sir, you in there?
主...
Si--
我必须告诉阿历克斯我们的事
I have to tell Alex about us.
你我  我们
Uh, "us" us?
这主意真差
No. that's a-- that's a bad idea.
-差得无与伦比  -这对他不公平
- That is monumentally bad. - it's not fair.
-你了解他  -是的  我不喜欢这样
- You know about him. - yeah, and I don't like it.
如果我能忘了他  我一定会
And if I could off him, I would.
他心情压抑又喜怒无常  我却很成熟
But he's the moody, broody one, whereas I am the mature and--
死了  你死了
Dead. you're dead.
我还活着  他也活着  我和他在一起很开心
I'm alive, and he's alive, and I'm happy when I'm with him.
你不希望我开心吗
Don't you want me to be happy?
伊兹  这是我毕生的追求
Iz, there isn't anything in this universe that I want more.
那我为何不能同时拥有你们两个
Then why can't I have you both?
这样我就会开心了
'cause that's what makes me happy.
他一定会把你当疯子
He's gonna think you're a whack job.
他告诉过我
He told me...
他爱我
That he loves me.
这对他来说实属不易
That's a huge deal for him.
我至少该对他坦诚
The least I can do is be honest.
医生的事很抱歉
Sorry about your doc.
没关系
Whatever.
肯利医生正准备签这个
Dr. Kenley was gonna sign this,
在他死前
Before he died and everything.
-你能否  -这是什么
- Can you?  - what is it?
我想许个愿
I want to get a wish from the wish people.
必须由医生来签字
You have to have a doctor sign it.
不  我才不签
No. I'm not signing that.
别看她  她也不会签的
Don't look at her. she's not gonna sign it either.
拜托  你签了就能帮我挑选愿望
Come on. look, if you sign, you can help me pick my wish.
这些是已经写下的愿望
These are the ones kids have already done,
例如看杂技表演或是牛仔表演
Like go on a circus trapeze or be in a rodeo.
你觉得哪些愿望不错就打个星号
Just put stars by the ones you think would be cool
觉得哪些愿望无聊就打叉
And x's by the ones you think are lame.
kenley不会打算签名的
There's no way Kenley was gonna sign that.
那是给患有致命性疾病的孩子准备的
That's for kids with life-threatening diseases.
你不会死  你只是病了
You're not dying. you're just sick.
小弟
Dude...
牛仔表演臭得像马粪
The rodeo smells like horse crap.
不去也罢
You're not missing anything.
我想  有个副甲状腺瘤等着你切除
I think... we've got a parathyroid tumor for you to remove.
-真的  -是的
- Really? - yeah.
你们在说肿瘤切除吗
Did I just hear tumor removal?
-我的住院医生抛弃了我  -你们需要帮手吗
- I--my resident abandoned me. - do you need any help?
-当然  -不
- Sure. - no.
也许  随便
Or... fine.
但你只准看  不准碰
But you'll watch. you're not touching anything.
懂了吗  不准碰
Get it? no touching.
她在楼上做超声检查
Uh, she's up in ultrasound.
-打电话问问好了没  -好的
- Call and see if they took her yet. - all right.
你跟她上床了
You slept with her?
绝对没有
Absolutely not.
就一次  她来旅馆找我
Only once. she came to my hotel room,
脱光了衣服让我"教她"
Took off all her clothes and said "teach me."
我大脑不听使唤
It was like I had no control.
她用裸体强暴了我
She violated me with her nakedness.
-德里克一定会杀了我  -你就不该和她独处
- Derek's gonna kill me. - well, you shouldn't have been alone with her.
绝不二犯
Never gonna happen again,
-尽管异常美妙  -你可是专业的
- Mind-blowingly fantastic as it was. - hey, you... are a professional,
-别忘了  -别动
- All right? - hey. oh, hold on.
千万别动
Hold tight.
有一根线  超声已经准备好
Just a bit of lint. um, ultrasound's backed up,
半小时内出结果
But they said they'll have results in half an hour.
好的  告诉格蕾
All right. uh, well, tell, uh, tell grey.
还有...告诉...
Uh, and, um, let, uh,
告诉...乔治  乔治医生
Let, uh, george-- dr. george--
告诉欧麦利医生  告诉他
Dr. O'malley know when, uh, let him know--
有结果了就告诉他  好吗
Let him know when you know, okay? okay.
你刚才还说到专业
You were saying something about professionalism.
你看到没
Well, uh, did, uh, did you see that?
那根线不是我头发里的
That--that was not in my head, right?
-告诉你  这些实习生都疯了  -冤魂不散
- I'm telling you, these interns are out of control. - stalkers.
饥渴的冤魂
Sexed-up stalkers.
贝利医生  我是arizona robbins
Dr. Bailey. Arizona Robbins.
我来接手肯利医生的病人
I'm taking over Dr. Kenley's patients.
你是儿科医生
You're the peds surgeon?
是的  我知道你参与杰克逊 普列斯科特的治疗
Yeah, I see you're assisting with Jackson Prescott.
并非对肯利医生不敬
You know, all due respect to Dr. Kenley--
他是位出色的医生  但我很惊讶
He was a wonderful physician-- but, you know, I'm surprised
他坚持这项治疗手段如此之久
That he followed this course of treatment for so long
明知该方法没有起效
When it wasn't, you know, working.
不  我不是责怪你
Oh, no. I'm not criticizing you.
-这不是你的决定  -但我支持这项决定
- I mean, you didn't make the call. - yeah, but I supported the call.
的确是尚未起效
Be--we hadn't turned the corner yet,
但kenley确信  如果继续保持
But Kenley was sure that if we kept doing
-现有治疗方式  -jack的病情十分严重
- What we were doing-- - Jack's case is quite severe.
-杰克逊  -你说什么
-Jackson. - Excuse me?
他叫杰克逊  如果你认为
Jackson is his name, and if you're suggesting
我们是以无用的治疗折磨他
That we were torturing him with useless procedures--
许多资深儿科医生
A lot of senior peds surgeons
都认为固塑法可以成功
Believe that stricturoplasty works,
-有时  他们是对的  -是的
- And sometimes they're right. - yeah--
所以今天就算了  但对于他的肝病
So we'll go with it today, but with his liver disease,
我们该寻找其他途径
We should start exploring other options.
我得走了  肯利医生的病人真多
I gotta run. Dr. Kenley had a big caseload.
手术室见
I'll see you in the O.R.
他依然十分痛苦  不知为什么
He's still in a lot of pain. I'm not sure why.
若能把他从背板上移下来就方便多了
It would help if we could get him off this backboard.
我们不该等X光吗
Shouldn't we wait for his x-rays?
他的右下肢开始麻木
He's got decreased sensation in his right lower extremity.
他说的而已
According to him.
他说的很可能是假的
He could tell you anything.
他注射了10单位的吗啡  他不该如此痛苦
We pushed 10 of morphine. he shouldn't be in this much pain.
也许该再注射一些
Maybe we could push a teeny bit more?
我们不是来给你减轻毒瘾的
You know, uh, we're not here to feed your drug habit.
我被关了11年
I've been behind bars for 11 years.
在那里吸毒可不是好主意
The drug trade in solitary isn't what one would hope.
-我们还是等拍片结果  -我觉得这是浪费时间
- Let's just wait for the films. - no, i-i think this is a waste of time.
我不喜欢同意杨的话
I hate to agree with Yang,
但我同意
But I agree with yang.
格蕾医生
Dr. Grey?
谢博德医生
Dr. Shepherd.
这是什么
What's that?
-刺伤他的物件还留在体内  -在他背里
- Whatever they stabbed him with is still in there. - in his back?
脊椎
Spine.
是不是意味着我瘫痪了
Uh, does that mean, uh, I'm paralyzed?
距离我的死刑期不到一周了
My--my execution date is in a week.
我已全力上诉
I've exhausted all my appeals.
但如果我瘫痪了  我的律师也许能
But i-if I'm paralyzed, my lawyer might be able
想法延缓执行
To make a case for staying my execution.
你们能让我变瘸吗
Do you think you could let me be a gimp?
不
No.
主任在里边吗  我要见他
Is the chief in there? I need to see him.
我也想见他  我们都要失望了
So do I. we're both gonna be disappointed.
他在里面干什么
Well, what exactly is he doing in there?
得知乔丹·肯雷出事后
Ever since he heard about jordan kenley,
他就一直待在里面  想一个人待着
He's been in there, and he wants to be alone.
我需要见...
I need to see...
此处脊髓有损伤
It's impinging on the spinal cord.
无法分辨脊髓是否被刺穿
I can't tell if it's going through or not
等CT结果出来就知道了
Well, we'll get a better picture once we get the c.t.s back.
我已经预约了核磁共振
I ordered an m.r.i.
CT未必能呈现出清晰的脊髓图像
The c.t. may not give us a clear view of the cord.
所有的图像都有那更好
We'll be happy to look at all the images.
我们会按照要求做
And we'll do everything by the book.
我可不希望他的律师以未得到应有治疗
I don't want some lawyer keeping him alive
为借口而让他活下去
On the basis that we did not give him the standard of care.
你赞同死刑
You're pro-death penalty?
-我只是赞同刑罚  -好人也会做错事
- I'm pro-punishment. - well, good people do bad things.
谁都会犯错  他也并非完人
People screw up. he's still a person.
-我们不知他所犯何罪  -也许是杀了个警察
- We don't know what crime he committed. - uh, maybe he killed a cop.
-我们同情杀警凶手  -我们不了解真相
Let's feel all warm for the cop killer. we don't know what he did.
我们没有发言权
We can't judge.
的确  但陪审团有权
No, but a jury can.
-死囚  -不敢相信我们竟浪费时间争论此事
- Death row - I can't believe we're wasting time debating this.
再做一次血容积检查  他若需要输血  告知我
Do a repeat crit, and let me know if he needs blood.
我以为她们是朋友
I thought they were friends.
曾经是
They were.
现在呢
And now?
现在我们俩这一天会非常非常漫长
Now you and I are in for a very, very long day.
闹别扭的姐妹请了个杀人魔
The annoying twins got a mass murderer.
-你觉得他们会买凶杀害对方吗  -不会
- Think one of 'em will pay the guy to off the other? - no.
就算他们的冲突升级
If they're gonna get violent,
最多就是自己动手
They'll probably just do it themselves.
-真怪异  她们居然闹矛盾  -是啊
- It's weird, right, them fighting? - yeah.
我有件事要告诉你
there's something that I need to talk to you about,
这件事情很怪异
And it's gonna sound weird.
你要知道  我也知道此事很怪异
And I want you to know that I know it sounds weird.
所以别被吓到
So just don't freak out.
-你要分手  -不  不是的
- You breaking up with me? - no, not at all.
这个主意不坏
Though that's not a bad idea.
我能看见丹尼
I see denny...
而且最近很频繁
A lot lately...
在医院
around here
还有房子里
And at the house.
你还好吧  听上去有点像疯了
Are you okay? 'cause that sounds kind of whacked.
我说的没错吧
what'd I tell you.
拜托  你祖母去世后你没见过她
Come on. you never saw your grandmother after she died?
见过  不过那是在梦里
Yeah. I mean, she showed up in a dream
告诉我说不要玩弄私处  但是...
And told me not to play with the parts, but...
没错  有点类似
Well... it's kinda like that.
什么
Excuse me?
-好吧  随便  -就这样
- All right. whatever. - that's it?
我不知道  代我向他问好
I don't know. tell him I said hi.
类似于他祖母跟他说不要...
Kinda like his gramother telling him not to
好吧  我退缩了
Okay, so I panicked.
顿先生  感觉好些了吗
Mr. dunn, are you feeling any better?
每个人都很关心我
everybody's been so attentive.
可我还是觉得很疼
I'm still in a lot of pain.
我们会把那东西从你背上取出来
Well, we're gonna get that thing out of your back
-越早越好  -你压住线了
- As soon as we can. - you're on the cord.
她...
She's...
她真够刻薄的
She's kind of a bitch.
不想讲粗话
Not--not to use coarse language,
但她确实如此
But she is.
她是我朋友
Well, she's my friend.
真的
Really?
我们正在闹矛盾
We had a fight
顿先生  有些信息对手术是很有帮助的
mr. dunn, it will really help us when we take it out
比如插进你背里的东西是什么
If we know what that thing in your back is.
我确信那是把牙刷
I'm pretty sure it was a toothbrush
有人把牙刷头折断  然后磨啊磨
And somebody snapped the head off and melted it down
磨到牙刷变成了刀
Till it was less toothbrush... and more knife.
怎么会插到你脊椎里的
How did it end up in your spine?
也是和朋友闹矛盾
Got in a fight with a friend.
美女
Hey, lady.
你能帮我吗
Can you help me?
当然  你还好吧
Sure. you feeling okay?
我没事  我将能实现一个愿望
Yaeh. You see, I'm gonna get a wish from the wish people,
但我对选哪一个愿望犹豫不决
But I'm having trouble deciding which wish to pick,
所以我想听听别人的意见
So I'm getting people's opinions.
给你喜欢的愿望打星号
You know, put stars by the ones you like
你觉得囧的愿望打叉
And x's by the ones you think are lame.
-然后你要签个名  -好吧
- Then you have to sign something. - okay.
去中国旅游怎么样  听起来很酷
how about a trip to China?that sounds cool
我晕飞机
I get airsick.
牛仔表演怎么样
the rodeo. how about the rodeo?
-有人说那闻起来像大便  -你在做什么
- Some guy said it smells like poo. - what the hell are you doing?
星号和大叉  我们在选愿望
Stars and x's, dude. we're picking wishes.
他根本不适用
he's not even eligible.
-你个小骗子  -你假装病危
- You're a little scammer. - you're fake dying?
-我想看牛仔表演  -你刚说那闻起来像大便
- I want to go to the rodeo. - well, you just told me it smells like poo.
好玩吧
Nice try.
来吧  我们开始做术前准备
Come on. let's get you prepped for surgery.
你告诉他了  他知道了
You told him. he knows.
别担心
Stop worrying.
你脖子上的小腺体里有个肿瘤
You've got a tumor on a little gland in your neck.
拜托
Come... on.
她经常这样
She does that.
玛格丽特  肿瘤是良性的
Margaret the tumor's benign,
摘除也不困难  哈里斯医生
And it's not hard to remove. dr. harris.
副甲状腺肿瘤令你的身体
A parathyroid tumor tells your body
不断从你的骨头里吸收钙质
To leech the calcium out of your bones.
所以你频频骨折
That's why you've had so many fractures.
肿瘤摘除后  你就可以回复正常
Once we take the tumor out, you'll be back to normal.
拜托  玛格丽特  这是好消息
Come on! margaret, this is good news.
我像个老妇一样活着
I've been living like an old lady.
我不能走楼梯  放弃了跑步和滑冰
I don't take the stairs, I gave up running, skiing.
我成天坐着织毛衣
I sit and I knit
并希望织东西时不要折了手指
And I hope that the knitting doesn't break a finger--
就因为这个肿瘤
All because of a tumor?
一个良性可去除的肿瘤
A tumor that's benign and easy to remove.
拜托
Come on!
曾经有个男人
There was a guy.
我爱他爱得死去活来
I fell in love with the most amazing guy.
他人好  床上功夫也一流
He was sweet kind best sex of my life
他不得不搬去丹佛
And he had to move to denver,
他希望我也一起去
And he wanted me to move with him,
我却不能  因为丹佛太冷
And I didn't because denver is icy.
太容易滑倒摔跤了
There were too many ways for me to slip and fall.
我的爱情飞了  浑身骨头都断了一遍
So I lose my guy and I break all these bones
都是因为这个吸骨肿瘤
From a bone-sucking tumor?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
不好意思  实验报告  斯隆医生
Sorry. from the lab, dr. sloan.
你还需要什么吗
Did you need something else?
这真是折磨
This is torture.
专心
Focus.
克莱夫  把牵引器拉大点
Okay karev can you pull the retractor more?
这样行吗
What, like that?
很好
Yeah, great.
见鬼
Damn.
看这里  这里一团糟
Look at this. it's a mess.
他需要将近10厘米的肠子
He's gonna have maybe 10 centimeters of bowel
-我们才能完成手术  -能否尝试比安奇疗法
- When we're done here. - can't we try a bianchi procedure,
试试能否多挽救一些
See if we can save more of it?
肠已坏死  而且肝硬化
the bowel's dead and the liver's cirrhotic.
-挽救不了什么  -但我们...
- I mean, there's no saving anything. - yeah, but we--
贝利医生  这孩子一年前就该接受移植
Dr. bailey, this kid should've been on a transplant list a year ago.
他能活到现在  已经是个奇迹
I mean, it's a miracle he's still alive.
这到底...
What are...
你在做什么呢
What are you doing?
今天我不见任何人  贝利
I'm not seeing anyone today, bailey.
我知道  但此事十分重要
Well, I know that, but this is important.
我的每次对话都很重要
Every conversation I have is important.
肯雷被人取代
Kenley has been replaced
穿着溜冰鞋上班的儿科医生亚利桑那
With an infant on roller skates named Arizona
她甚至懒得给自己改个名字
Who didn't have sense enough to change her name
叫什么不好  叫亚利桑那  可见判断力有多差
To something other than arizona, which shows poor judgment,
她对病人的诊断同样如此
As does her diagnosis of a patient
我对病人治疗了三年
That I've been working with for three years.
她完全改变了肯雷的治疗计划
She's completely changing kenley's treatment protocol
她跟孩子才相处了半小时就做出了决定
Based on,like,half an hour of experience with the child.
我们刚取出了他的大部分肠子
I mean, we just took out most of his bowel,
当我们想尝试保住剩下的部分
And instead of trying to salvage what he has left,
她就想甩手不干了
She just wants to throw up her hands
转而期望得到器官移植
And pray for a transplant.
这孩子个把月都在吃流食
Look,the child hasn't eaten solid food in months.
一年来都没有发育  他的肝脏也受损
He--he hasn't grown in years. his liver is shot.
病情如此严重
It is a serious case.
我们需要有人能解决这个问题
Now we need someone who can handle it.
贝利医生
Dr. bailey...
你觉得谢博德只是徒有其表
You thought shepherd was just a haircut.
你不喜欢汉娜
You didn't like hahn.
你觉得斯隆医生是个淫棍
And you think dr. sloan is a... hussy.
你有对哪个主治医师感到满意吗
Can you name any attending that you thought was good?
我一直是你粉丝
I've always been a fan of your work.
亚利桑那·罗宾斯是班内的佼佼者  跟你一样
Arizona robbins was top of her class, like you.
她曾是主住院医师  跟你一样
And she was chief resident, like you.
她是多年来人们公认的第一
And she's the best anyone's seen in a long time,
也跟你一样
Just like you.
我们只有她  没有别人
She is who we have. we don't have anyone else.
接受现实
Deal with it.
这是干嘛
What's that for?
貌似今天你朋友不多
Seems like you're short of a friend today,
所以我来充个数
So I thought I'd fill in.
随便你  同事不是朋友  是竞争对手
Whatever. colleagues aren't friends. they're competitors.
这么说你不喝这杯咖啡
so does that mean you're not gonna drink this coffee?
不是  我要喝
No, I'll... I'll drink the coffee.
核磁共振显示他脑部受到擦伤
M.r.i.--he's got brain contusions
先处理这个
On top of everything else.
顿先生还是很疼
Mr. dunn is still in a huge amount of pain.
我能给他更多的吗啡吗  是否会对神经检查
Can I give him more morphine, or will that cause problems
造成不利影响  顿先生的吗啡够量了
With his neuro exams? mr. dunn has had enough morphine.
是的  但他身上插有异物
Right, but he's got a foreign body
就插在脊椎里  这样不人道
Lodged in his spine. it's inhumane.
不  杀人才不人道
No, killing people is inhumane.
不给他止疼是他活该
Denying him pain killers is a judgment call.
德瑞克
Derek...
你今天怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我成天看着人在死
I watch people die all the time.
我走向他们的家人  告诉他们
I go to families and I tell them
他们的世界从此破碎了
Their world has been ripped apart all the time.
我拼命工作就
And I fight like a dog to make sure
就是为了不用传递这种消息
That I don't have to deliver that message,
可我一直失败
And I lose that fight all the time.
之后  登这样的人出现了
Then some guy like dunn comes along
就这样无视生命
And simply throws it away--life?
他就能理直气壮得告诉我
Then he's got the nerve to tell me
他和我是硬币的正反两面
That he and I are two sides of the same coin?
你不是
You're not.
他不需要吗啡
He doesn't need morphine.
她是如此精致
She's exquisite.
不单单是性  我们聊了很久
And it's not just the sex. we talked for hours...
还笑了
And laughed.
这只是性
It's just the sex.
难道你没有想赛迪
Yeah, you're gonna tell me you're not thinking about sadie?
没想
Nope.
没有  我不能发生另一段...
No, I cannot... have another...
愚蠢的罗曼蒂克
Stupid romantic...
在这个医院是灾难  尴尬
Disaster in this hospital.it's embarrassing.
你的确有大量的历史记录
You do have quite a track record.
好吧  我们需要...
All right, you know what? we need to...
我们需要想点别的
We need to find something else to think about.
值得一试
Worth a try.
不行  没用
Nope. not working.
不行
Nope.
好吧
Okay.
我们就像瘾君子  对吗
okay. we're like addicts, right?
我们需要一个12步治疗计划
We need a 12-step program.
我才不会跟别人讨论我看上了
I'm not going to a meeting to discuss my obsession
我最好朋友的女友的同父异母的妹妹  绝不
With my best friend's girlfriend's half sister. no, no, no.
只有我们俩
It'll just be us.
我们互为保证人
We'll be each other's sponsors,
监督我们在按照计划做
Make sure we stay on the program.
有哪些步骤
What are the steps?
不要在实习医生面前赤裸
Don't get naked with an intern.
其实更像是一步计划
It's more of a one-step program.
-也许我该写下来  -好的
- Maybe I should write this down. - yeah, okay.
克里斯蒂娜
Hey, cristina.
你知道今天是伊兹的生日吗
Can you mention that it's izzie's birthday today?
今天有人应该表示点什么
Because someone should do something about it.
我在计划一个聚会
I myself am planning a party
-有气球  彩旗和狂欢  -好主意
- With balloons, streamers and a bouncy house. - oh, that's a good idea.
但你知道吗  阿历克斯应该做点什么
But you know what? alex should do something about it.
-我知道  长舌妇  一切尽在掌握  -狂欢吗
- I know, hosebag. I got it under control. - oh, a bouncy house?
他在这儿吗
Is he here?
谁
Who?
你朋友
Your friend.
没  他不在这儿
No, he's not here.
那好  如果他出现
Well, if he shows up,
告诉他我能分享女友  但是三明治不行
Tell him I'll share my girl but not my sandwich.
我花了4美元啊
This thing cost 4 bucks.
我吃完了
I'm done here.
核磁共振的家伙被那死囚吓死了
The dude from m.r.i. was all freaked out about death row guy.
不能带着手铐做检查
Couldn't put his cuffs in the machine,
他们只能用尼龙绳捆住他
So they had to velcro him to the table.
有个技工担心他会扯破绳子
The tech thought he was gonna tear it all off
然后像绿巨人那样拆了整间房子
And storm the booth like the hulk or something.
那他做了什么
what did he do?
-不知道  我猜他躺着完成了核磁共振  -不
- I don't know. I guess he laid there and had the m.r.i. - no.
他做了什么而被判死刑
What did he do to get on death row?
他杀了一大群人
Did he mow down a bunch of people
机关枪杀手
With a machine gun?
也许发现老婆和妓男以及杂役有奸情
Probably found his wife in bed with a hooker and a handyman.
因冲动而杀人是不会判死刑的
They don't give you the death penalty for crimes of passion.
-人们能够理解  -哪个犯罪不是由于冲动
- People understand that. - all crimes are crimes of passion.
总有原因的  人们不会因为忘记了此事非法
There's always a reason. people don't do stuff like that
才去做的
Because they forget it's illegal.
你杀她的时候
When you kill her,
是否会是冲动导致的犯罪
Is it gonna be a crime of passion?
-还在闹别扭呢  -不  没什么大不了的
- That still hasn't blown over? - no. it's not a big deal.
我们吵架了  她闹得过分了  仅此而已
We had a fight. she took it too far. that's all.
想知道我怎么想的吗
wanna know what I think?
不怎么想
Not really.
我想尖叫或者是杀人
I need to scream or kill someone,
我更倾向于杀人
Though I'm leaning towards killing someone.
工作中
working.
我感觉好多了  谢谢
I'm feeling much better. thanks.
不论你给我注射了什么  谢谢你
Thank you for whatever it was you gave me.
你有没有家人
Is there a-a family
或者其他人需要告知你要做手术
Or someone who should know you're having surgery?
我们不能通知你的家人
Well, we can't call your family.
我想她要问的是
I think what she's trying to ask you is,
-你犯了什么事被判死刑的  -你不用回答
- What did you do to get on death row? - you don't have to answer that.
我不是想问这个
That was not what I was asking.
我不介意  这个问题人人都想问
Well, I don't mind. it's an obvious question.
某个星期一 我割破了这个女人的喉咙
One monday   I slit this woman's throat.
我想着干这事好一段时间了
I had been thinking about it for a while
做梦也想着
Dreaming about it
一个星期一 我就
And one monday   I just...
我忍不住
I had to do it.
我只是
I just...
非常想在她脖子上割一刀
Really wanted to draw a knife across her neck.
我以为我会被吓死的
And i-i thought it would be terrifying
或者感到悲凉或什么的  但是我没有
Or... or sad or something   but it wasn't.
我只是觉得
It was just...
挺有趣的
Kind of fun.
我星期二又割了两个
So I did two more on tuesday
星期三又割了两个
Another two on wednesday.
我原本还打算星期四割三个的
I was gonna go for three on thursday
因为我喜欢星期几就几个人这样的配对
'cause I liked the alliteration
但是我被捉了  那就割不成了
But I got caught so I didn't.
能给我点果冻吃吗
Could I get some jell-o?
看看这签名
Read the sign.
-有人叫我不要理这些签名  -不能不理
-I was told to ignore the sign.  -well   don't.
贝利 告诉我
Bailey told me.
我要杀了那个女的
I'm gonna kill that woman.
听好 我
Look   i   uh
我并不是太了解kenley
I didn't know kenley all that well
但是  这有点难受
But it--it's gotta be tough
失去了一个长期一起工作的同事
Losing a coworker you worked with for a long time.
约旦 肯利个狗娘养的
Jordan kenley was a son of a bitch.
跟小孩相处地很好  精通手术
Great with kids   good with a scalpel
但对同事的态度很差
But horrible to his colleagues.
他好胜  缺乏安全感  又咄咄逼人
He was competitive   insecure   aggressive.
我一点都不想念他
I won't miss him for a minute.
那么  这是因为你在想着自己的死亡路吗
So... is this about your mortality?
我并不担心死去
I'm not worried about me dying
或者约旦 肯利的死
Or jordan kenley dying.
我担心的是我的医院会走下坡
I'm worried about my hospital dying.
我打了几个电话  找人代替肯利
I made some calls to replace kenley.
没有人想来我们医院
No one wants to come here.
我连一个心脏外科医生都留不住
I can't keep a cardiac surgeon on staff.
布克辞职  翰又辞职  迪克逊又自闭
Burke quit. hahn quit. dixon's autistic.
我的手术房要崩塌了  整个地方都要被洪水淹没了
My o.r. roof collapsed. the whole place flooded.
那些实习生狗咬狗
The interns are literally
狠不得打对方切成小块
Chopping each other into little pieces.
怪不得我们排第12  第12啊
No wonder we're number 12. 12.
我整一生都贡献在这家医院  却失败了
I failed at the one thing I spent my whole life doing.
一败涂地
Failed.
所以我打算就躺在这张桌子上
So I'm gonna stay right here on this table
一直到我找到方法
Until I find a way
能让我毫不畏惧地在踏进大厅向前走
To walk the halls without cringing
你不是应该向我说教
Aren't you supposed to give me
鼓励我"打起精神  重回正轨"的吗
That rousing "get back on the horse" lecture?
我得去帮一个连环杀手缝针
I have gotta stitch a serial killer
今天得将他缝好
Back together today.
我才不会说什么鼓励你的话
I don't have a rousing lecture in me.
我们需要一个战略
We're gonna need a strategy--
她们性感的眼睛紧盯着我们每一个举动
Their hot little eyes tracking our every move.
好  不能随意地看肩膀
Okay   no   uh... casual glances over the shoulder.
不能说"这很有趣  每个人都能看吗"
No "this is interesting. can everybody see?"
我们一旦切除了马格利特的肿瘤
As soon as margaret's tumor is out
我们就让她们把肿瘤拿去病理科分析
We'll have them take it to pathology to get it analyzed.
好  加油  暂停一下
Right. go   team. break.
他们还在冷战吗
They still not speaking?
看着不像喔
It doesn't look like it.
在冰窖两小时
Wow. two hours in an ice cave.
帮年度西雅图强人做手术  至少我们能互相支持
Working on seattle's man of the year. well   at least we got each other.
你知道  我们能装作没看到
You know   we can pretend not to notice
说点海鹰队或者其他的
Talk about the seahawks or something.
或者我们现在就走  去喝点啤酒
Or we could just take off   go grab a beer
让他们把刀拔出来吧  一步一步来
Let them pull out the shiv. onward and upward.
我觉得我之前说得不够清楚
I don't think I was clear earlier.
那并不是梦境
It is not like a dream.
在我清醒的时候我看到丹尼  我们一起玩
I see denny when I'm awake. we hang out.
因为我说我爱你
This is because I said I loved you.
你吓坏了  我没有
You're freaked out. I'm not.
你有点吓着了
You're a little freaked out.
我们还
Um   we still...
一起做点事
Do stuff together.
性事
Sex stuff.
我看到他  而且我们做爱了
I see him   and... we have sex.
有点美好的幻想不坏啊
There's nothing wrong with a good fantasy.
我意思是  我宁愿你幻想的对象是我
I mean   I'd rather you fantasize about me
或者一些靓女
Or chicks...
-但什么都好  -你真的不介意
-But whatever. -you really don't care?
你努力地想理清自己的思绪
You're trying to work somethinout.
我意思是  人死了
I mean   people die
然后其他人  你明白的
And then the other people   you know
就会因此把生活搞得乱糟糟
Get messed up about it.
对啊  但是
Yeah   but--
伊兹  我与那个幻想工具竞争了很久了
Iz   I've been competing with that tool for a long time.
我想说  他现在算是有点身体障碍了
I'd say he's kind of got the handicap now.
我指  他在这里吗  他能看到我这么做吗
I mean   is he here? can he see me do this?
看到啊  小子  我看到你
Yeah   dude. I can see you.
能看到我做这个吗
And this?
他还在吗
Is he still here?
我认为你该走了
I think you should go.
是的  我有事情要做
Yeah   I got things to do.
你现在能看到他吗
Can you see him now?
不了  他走了  不要停
No. no   he's gone. don't stop.
不要停  那现在呢
Don't stop. what about now?
不  不要停
No   don't stop.
很锋利
sharp.
难道你整天在抱怨
No wonder he was complaining so much.
多注射10克吗啡
He wasn't complaining after he got 10 extra of morphine.
他多注射了10克吗啡
He got an extra 10 of morphine?
是  那就使他舒服多了
Yes   and it made him much more comfortable.
你不烦恼吗  这个人本有可能
It doesn't bother you that this guy probably hacked
用一把弯刀把一家四人都杀死了
A family of four to death with a machete?
是一把刀  和女人  不是一家子
A knife   and women   not a family.
五个女人  他喜欢
Five women. it's what he likes.
你们根本不可以为他做手术  你们俩都不行
You shouldn't even be on this case   either of you.
他能做出什么呢  跳下手术台刺杀我们
What's he gonna do   jump off the table and get us?
拿到的人是你
You're the one holding the knife.
我们有一个肾切除手术要做
We'll be doing a nephrectomy.
你们中有人动过肾门吗
Either one of you ever mobilize the renal hilum?
我没有做过  但是我想试一下
Uh   I've never done one   but I'd love to try.
我在尸体上练习过  百千遍
I've practiced on cadavers probably hundreds of times.
所以这不会是我第一次动刀
It wouldn't be my first try.
这么说  对于部分人  手术自然而来
Oh   well   to some of us   surgery comes naturally
其他人要练习
Others have to practice.
你有看上礼拜海鹰队的比赛吗
You see the seahawks game last week?
你知道  我很容易就吃醋
You know   I am the jealous type.
我知道  对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
我不做选择  请不要逼我作选择
I can't choose. please don't make me choose.
你要我选吗
Are you gonna make me?
我不会做让你不开心的事
I can't do anything that would make you unhappy.
你知道的
You know that.
我爱你
I love you.
你对每个人都这么说
That's what you tell all the guys.
你知道  今天是我生日
You know   today is my birthday.
我真的知道
I do know that.
你要送我礼物吗
You gonna get me a present?
我刚才不是送了吗
I think I just did.
为什么她在摇头
Why is she shaking her head?
她在看杰克逊手术后的肝功能检查结果
Jackson's post-op l.f.t.s.
这小孩今天应该列入移植名单
This kid needs to be put on the transplant list today.
肠  或者肝也要
Just the intestine   or-- liver   too.
我想我们应该听听别人的意见
I think we should get another opinion.
霍普金斯的诺曼 马克  儿科手术的头儿
Norman mccale at hopkins. head of pediatric surgery.
告诉他亚利桑那派你来的  他告诉你什么
Tell him arizona sent you. when he tells you
那个杰克逊需要器官移植
That jackson needs a transplant
他会在两分钟内打电话申请
Which he'll do about two minutes into the call
-把他列入移植名单  -可以  没必要这么凶对我说
-Put him on the list. -okay   there's no need to snap at me.
事实上 有必要
There is   actually.
我进来的那一秒开始  你就在猜度我
You've been second-guessing me from the moment I arrived.
我明白的  你喜欢肯利医生
And I get it. you liked dr. kenley.
你信任他  而我是一个扎马尾的陌生人
You trusted him   and I'm a stranger with a ponytail.
但问题不在我  病人才是医治的对象
But I'm not the problem. the patient is.
那你能不能不要想我
So how about you stop thinking about me
而是把集中力都集中在他身上  jackson需要器官移植
And start focusing on him? jackson needs a transplant
如果我们继续浪费时间  他就不能移植了
And if we keep wasting time   he's not gonna make it.
你还好吧  想出去喝一杯或者做点什么吗
You okay? you wanna get a drink or something?
我们又好起来了吗  是因为气氛正合你心意吗
Oh. oh   now we're on again 'cause the mood suits you?
因为我是没有朋友的悲伤小女孩吗
'cause I'm the sad little girl with no friend
我跌倒了  你这个救世主就开始行动了  我并不
And I tripped your savior complex into action? i-i don't--
通常情况  我对这种热情冷漠之间的事儿都能运筹帷幄
Usually I can deal with the hot-and-cold thing
但今天不能
But not today.
他妈的  让我自己静一下
Just leave me the hell alone.
是他吗
Is that him?
你发现他做了什么吗
You ever find out what he did?
他做了什么都没关系
It doesn't matter what he did.
他做的事可恶透了
He did something really bad
他要为之付出代价的
And he's gonna pay for it.
你想去喝一杯吗
You want to get a drink?
没心情呢
Oh. I'm not in the mood.
你知道  我跟你之前也有过这样的吵架
You know   you and I had a fight like this once.
什么
What?
阿姆斯特丹
Amsterdam.
我们之前想你跟克丽斯提娜的关系那么亲密
We used to be as close as you and cristina
阿姆斯特丹事件发生了  你开始不理我了
And then amsterdam happened and you shut me down
我们跨不过这个坎
And we never got past it.
我们还一起玩啊  但是不像以前
We still hung out   but--but not like before.
我们出去跳舞
We'd go dancing
去嘈杂的地方 我们就不用聊天
Go someplace loud where we don't have to talk.
那也行  我见异思迁  我跳跃前进
And that's okay. I'm a-- I'm a rolling stone. I bounce.
但是你现在又要这么对克丽斯提娜
But you're about to do the same thing to cristina
那女孩可以能够一生结伴的朋友啊
And that girl mates for life.
如果你处理不好
If you don't make it right
她永远都不会跟你说话
She'll never talk to you again.
我道歉了  向克丽斯提娜道歉
I apologized... to cristina.
你真心的吗
Like you meant it?
你能听出道歉的重点吗
Like you could imagine she had a point?
我想你
I miss you.
你是我的朋友  我想你
As my friend   I miss you.
器官移植不简单
Now transplants aren't easy.
这是坏消息
That's the bad news.
但是好消息是
But the good news is
你有一个能力非凡的新医生
You've got a crackerjack new doctor.
我问了一个备受尊重的儿科医生
Um   I spoke to one of the most respected kid surgeons
全国范围内的
In the country
他觉得她是最优秀的
And he thinks that she's the best there is.
所以她会好好照顾你  我们也会
So she's gonna take good care of you. we all are.
要不我们出去
Hey   why don't we go out and   um
在移植同意书上签字
Uh   sign some of the transplant consent forms?
画星星和交叉
Stars and x's.
气色不错  margaret
Looking good   margaret.
手术非常顺利
The surgery couldn't have been smoother.
我什么时候才能出院  快了
When can I get out of here? soon.
你年轻  痊愈得很快的  想着回家
You're young. you'll heal fast. eager to get home?
我要去丹佛
I'm going to denver.
我们今天表现不错
We did good work today.
如果我们一直表现坚强
If we stay strong...
不喝醉
Don't get drunk...
一直看着乔  那我们就没事了
Keep staring at joe   we'll be fine.
需要点什么吗
Hi. get you anything?
好啊  我觉得你们很奇怪
Okay   y-you're weirding me out.
生命只有一次
You only live once.
不要浪费生命
You can't waste it.
不 马克  不要
No. nomark. no.
看着乔  看着  看乔
Look at joe. look at-- look at me. look at me.
小孩  对不起
Sorry   kid.
我要去丹佛
I'm going to denver.
不要  马克  回来  不
No. mark. mark   come back here. no.
马克  不要
Mark   no.
他妈的
Damn it.
妈的  妈的  妈的
Damn it. damn it. damn it.
要再喝一杯吗  要
You need another drink? yes!
她没事  arizona robbins
She's all right. arizona robbins.
我不知道病人能不能熬过去
I don't know if the patient's gonna make it   th--
易事  我们不需许愿
We don't wish for the easy stuff.
我们求的是大事
We wish for big things...
雄心勃勃的事
Things that are ambitious...
无法企及的事
Out of reach.
看一下
Let's take a look.
两个人向我爸开枪
Two guys shot my dad...
想要他的手表
For his watch.
手表是我妈存钱买的
My mom saved up for it.
两个人走进士多
Two guys came into his store
他们开枪  因为我爸不愿放弃手表
And they shot him because he wouldn't give it up.
我爸就这样死了
That's how my dad died.
我们应该对每个人都公平
We are supposed to treat everybody the same.
但是不是每个人都一样的
But they're not all the same.
对不起
I'm sorry.
整天都很糟  我猜是吧
Just a bad day all around   I guess.
我希望我能够在你与克丽斯提娜的事上帮点忙
I wish I could make things better with you and cristina.
我也希望你可以
I wish you could   too.
我试着猜想她会做什么
I tried to think what she would do
在这种情况下  但是  我不知道
In a situation like this   but... I don't know.
她会  可能  把音乐调得很大声
Well   she would   uh   turn the music up pretty loud
然后跟我跳舞  把烦恼一并跳掉
And she would dance it out with me.
但我觉得你不想跳舞
But I don't think you want to go there.
这嘛
Well...
看看我们现在有什么音乐
Let's see what we got here.
小心
Look out.
来吧  起来
Come on   get up.
抬起你的屁股  我一个人跳不了舞
Get your ass over here. I'm not doing this by myself.
这就对了
There you go.
我们许愿是因为我们需要帮助
We wish because we need help...
是因为心里害怕
And we're scared...
我们知道可能自己要求太多
And we know we may be asking too much.
天啊
Oh   my god.
你做的
You made it?
这蛋糕吃上去很过瘾
The cake tastes kind of funny
但糖霜挺不错的
But the frosting's pretty good.
很好看
It's beautiful.
这个做法很不错
It's a nice gesture
他为我做蛋糕
Him baking for you.
许愿
Make a wish.
如果我没有愿要许呢
What if I don't have anything to wish for?
如果我已经拥有希望得到的一切呢
What if I have everything I could ever want?
但是  我们还是会许愿
We still wish   though...
希望保持现状
Then wish that nothing changes.
因为
Because...
有时
Sometimes...
愿望会成真
They come true.